all right boys and girls hunting season
archery season actually is right around
the corner just a few days away from
whitetail opening up down here
a lot of areas whitetails already opened
up but anyways
part of that means that um you're going
to have
to have the proper equipment
after you harvest your deer or kill your
deer i'm sorry if that bugs people but i
like to say kill because we're not
picking
deer out of the ground we're we're
taking their lives and then we're
eating them and if that bothers some
people i apologize but
i don't like mixing terms anyways
how there is a squirrel in that tree
right there and he looks super tasty and
i hate to
get sidetracked but i do have add and if
that sucker is still there at the end of
this video
y'all will see some a squirrel recipe on
my facebook page
later on today because i will eat that
sucker by the time this
day is over with anyways back to deer
so last year uh blackwater had 612
clients
so that is a lot of animals that have to
be skin caped and quartered
that is also a lot of extremely proud
ladies and gentlemen um showing off
their favorite
hunting knife and how they skin and cape
and quarter stuff
mind you we do probably 95
of everything that gets killed um
in our company myself or one of the guys
that work for blackwater
will do the skin caping and quartering
but there are a lot of
clients or a few clients that prefer to
do it themselves and enjoy it and they
they have their favorite knife or
favorite way of of doing that
i will tell you this from experience and
as a side note
blackwater's still a small channel we
have no sponsors
okay we do have some guides and outfit
or discounts from different companies
that are kind enough to do that for any
guide or outfitter out there not just
us anybody that is a guide or outfitter
and has
proper documentation to show that i
guess you would say
can go and get these discounts however
the company that i
prefer to use i have yet to find
a guide or outfit or discount on so the
product that i
choose as my favorite product um i pay
full price for
just like anybody else does i actually
bought a new one just for this video
so i wouldn't be showing a bunch of old
bloody
you know unclean stuff on here but
anyways i picked it up at cabela's
uh yesterday um just so i could show you
guys
and um keep in mind that
i'm i'm probably not the best in the
world
at this we we like to joke around about
how fast we can do it now there's two
giant eurasian dove right there sitting
on my kid's playhouse
that i could smoke also and have
squirrel and dove for lunch and this is
driving me crazy that i'm trying to do
this video right now
and i've got all this great food sitting
out here in front of my truck because
the rain just finally stopped
anyways so i got the new knife so i
could show you guys how to do this
and i will cut to that um like i said
i'm
i'm i might not be the best in the world
of this but um
we are probably faster than most and get
to experience cleaning deer
more than the average person like i said
we had 612 hunters last year
and we very rarely if ever
have guys that leave camp without taking
an animal so that's
that's a lot of animals that we get to
skin cape and quarter each year
so to jump to it so that i don't make
this 30 minutes long
my go-to my very favorite i think the
best
product out on the market for you
to skin cape and quarter a deer with or
any animal because we do all kind of
animals
but whether you've got a skinning rack
or whether you're in the field when it
happens
my favorite product is the
havalon talon set okay this is new i
think they came out with this last year
if i'm not mistaken it's going to cost
you about 75 bucks give or take a few
dollars depending on where you buy it
but any any hunting knife that's
that's actually worth um having is going
to cost you around that
amount of money i know some people argue
with me and say you know i've had my
grandpappies that cost him 12
in 1942 and it still skins deer good and
that's awesome
that's awesome and and the nostalgia of
that and the heritage and the history
awesome you'll never find somebody that
gets pumped up about
old-time hunting stuff more than myself
but
for the things that i use this for and
the amount of animals that i skin cape
and quarter every year
i have never found a better product than
the havalon talon
and i have used pretty much everything
on the market
with the exception of the raptor razor
stuff i've never used those i've seen a
lot of people use them they do look cool
i'm not sure how that would fit my hand
and you know there's i haven't found a
place i could just pick one up and i
i kind of hate ordering stuff online if
i've never actually got to play with it
before
so that's probably the reason i've never
used a raptor razor knife
but this right here is my go-to and i'll
open it up and show you guys
so you do get this packet i usually just
roll it back up when i'm done stick it
right back in my ranger
i got one in the ranger one in the truck
everywhere i go i've got this with me
i've also got a knife box that i keep in
the back if i go do
hunts that are not around the skin and
shed that i can open up my game cleaning
box and i've got
all my game cleaning bags um gloves for
people that like to wear gloves
knives extra blades and
hand wipes so when you're done you can
clean up and and trash bags in there so
that you throw your trash in the trash
bag and not
out on the ground somewhere anyways this
opens up
it's got a place for uh your actual
knife handle here
and then your blades as as they go the
cool thing about this
is that you can it comes with
okay i'll just show you you get this
handle here
all right and it looks just like kind of
the
regular avalons do with the little clip
the insert there
but on this one it has a a small lever
that you just
or a button that you push and that
allows you to clip in or release
it also has this which is really nice
but this locks it to where
no matter what you do you can't get that
blade off that's extremely important
especially when you're messing around
with havalons because
havalons
are obviously surgical blades and
they're extremely
sharp and so it's extremely easy to cut
yourself and cut yourself
bad with a havalon so
having the ability to lock it to where
you're not in a deer and that slip off
the blade slip off which i have
experienced in the past with some of the
other
havalons you know you go in to make a
cut and
the blade kind of gets stuck and you
pull back on your cut and the whole
thing pops off well your hand's still
there
and it will slice the piss out of you
when you do that
but this keeps it locked in so that's
not going to happen i think that is a
huge new attribute that these knives
have and a great safety feature
that these guys have have built into
this
when you buy this it comes with
two of the three inch with the gut hook
uh
just slick beveled edge blades
it comes with one
serrated three inch sorry i didn't put
that on screen good
and then it comes with one of the
i believe this is the five inch that it
comes with a fillet type deal
you can also get a seven it also has
spots for seven inch and nine
inch have one uh the company does make
the
seven inch and nine inch replaceable
blades um which are great if you're
going to
do stuff like deboning meat um
cutting cinnamon out of meat the whole
nine yards anything like that or if you
just like a longer
longer knife blade to work with
obviously it's
it's good for that too i've also used
that on fish for laying fish
the nine inch blades do have a good bend
to them and you can fillet the fish and
it's
it's good to go um
the serrated edge blade never have used
one of those
and any of these havalon towns i've
bought i've never used this i've
probably got
six of these blades just from the
original packages that i've never used
i've never found a use for the serrated
edge
while i'm skinning taping or quartering
an animal
and so therefore i've i've never used
that one i wish
that they would just i almost wish they
would take that out and
give you another of the smooth bevel
edge blades
but i'm sure there's people out there
that use a serrated for something or
they would not continue to put them in
there
these blades right here the serrated
beveled edge blades absolutely fantastic
they have a gut hook on them and that
gut hook is legit man
an easy easy 100 animals that you can
use that gut hook on without it going
dull on you
so that is a huge plus for me because i
don't care how good you are
with a regular knife or with this
portion this side
of a regular blade you cannot
zip an animal faster than a guy with a
gut hook can
okay so if it's hanging you can go up on
the legs where you've made your inserts
to put your gamble in
and you can go one two all the way down
no problem and it's it's done like that
if you're going to cape around something
instead of sitting there and flopping
hurt hair everywhere or trying to get
your knife underneath it without poking
the belly
you can go right here and you can zip
completely around that deer
deer to tube it and and start caping it
out
so huge benefit to have
the razor sharp surgical blades with a
freaking awesome gut hook on it
okay and you get two of these in the
package
all right another big benefit because
avalon used to not have these um you
know these type blades it used to just
always be those
68s or 70s or whatever
um surgical blades now they have these
so everybody at one point was telling me
you got to switch to outdoor edge you
got to switch to outdoor edge you got a
bigger blade a bigger handle it's easier
to use
i did i switched to outdoor edge for
just a little bit
if you look at the outdoor edge their
knife blade
is about this
as far as how um
i don't know what the word would be but
how tall it is it's very
short blade that just attaches to the
main blade on or the main receiver on
the outdoor edge
it's it's kind of flimsy
it's not fun to get in and get out
and i i just didn't like it you end up
you end up running your actual
receiver portion on the meat and on the
hide
way you know way too much in my opinion
whereas this
gives you the entire width of an actual
blade
to use the handle portion doesn't touch
any part of your meat hair or hide
this is also an extremely thick
blade you could i don't want to do it
too hard because i'll slip and cut the
piss out of myself but
you can bend try to bend that as much as
you want and you're not bending that
blade
you can take those outdoor edge blades
and you can bend them right in half if
you want to
this is like a real knife blade
that that just clips into your
into your handle here so basically and
it comes with these points so you don't
stab yourself getting it out of the
package
but basically all you do is you push
down
first of all make sure it's unlocked you
push down on that you clip that in you
let it go
lock it back in boom and you're on there
not coming off you've got
a great handle to be able to use it's
tough it's got good grips on there in
case it's wet
you're not going to slip off of there
it's even got a thumb portion on the
back side of it
to where when you're using a gut hook
you can push your thumb up against that
and really and really slice down that
stuff great and then if you go to
it's got the thumb on the back and it's
got the same uh indention on the front
so when you start caping or slicing or
whatever you got that
um to get it out all you got to do
is push that button again boom pop it
right back out you're good to go
for 70 you cannot purchase
a better hunting knife i shouldn't say
hunting knife for 70 dollars you cannot
purchase a better skinning caping and
quartering knife
than what havalon has put in to the
havalon talon series
especially considering you've got the
pack
that you can put your blades back in you
can put your knife handle back in
you can wrap it back up clip it back
together and everything stays there
because losing knife handles and losing
blades
when you use surgical type blade
equipment
is a huge negative right now and this
packet
makes things 10 times better when you're
able to just put stuff back where they
go
everything has its own spot you're able
to put it back where it goes and keep
that with you
um really forever they've got
all these blades that i'm talking about
are all sold also as replaceables so
once you buy the 70
set at from that point forward all you
have to do from
from then out for or i guess i should
say from then on
is uh just replace the blades also if
you get a bunch of crap
inside your knife and um and you need to
clean it you can actually
unlock it and take every one of these
things apart the knife will actually
come apart in the middle
you can clean everything out if you're
one of those neat freak type guys you
can clean everything out and restore it
till it's brand new again
put it all back together and then put it
back in the pack
i'm not that guy so i just hit it with
the power washer
and put it back in the back but
point being for a knife
to use skinning caping and quartering in
our industry today
there is not one that is better made
than the havalon talon series
i suggest you go get one i know they
sell them online
they sell them at cabela's i've never
seen havalon products sold in academy
which is a texas thing um but i do know
they sell them in cabela's bass pro shop
and those are pretty much
in every state now so if you're looking
for one
go get you one they don't pay me to say
this i just skinned a
skin cape and quarter a whole bunch of
animals and i'm letting you guys know
that in my opinion
this is as good as it gets hope you
enjoyed this review
you got anything else you want to see
please let us know
your asian doves still on top of there
and the squirrel's still in the tree
i'm about to go get me some lunch